Mauricio Cardozo

São Paulo, Brazil (EST Timezone)

profile

Mauricio is a UX focused Senior iOS Engineer passionate about multi-platform development in the Apple ecosystem, with 5+ years of experience in both small and large teams.

contact info

email mauricio.cardozo@me.com GitHub @loloop linkedin/in/mauricio-cardozo iMessage +55 11972332444

experience

Senior iOS Engineer at Primer (San Francisco - Remote, 2021-2023)

Primer is an early stage education startup working to free the next generation of kids to be more ambitious, more creative, and to think for themselves

- Engineer #2 on a team with a large, deeply modularized, multi-platform iOS, iPadOS and macOS codebase, making sure the user experience on all platforms was prioritized
- · Architected the social feed and class scheduling logic across 5 different feature modules
- Shipped a growth experiment for Inktober in 5 days for a new club that grew to have DAUs that equaled to that of the rest of the app combined
- Set-up and scaled snapshot testing infrastructure to hundreds of snapshots tested in CI across several different features
- Implemented a social inspiration cataloging feature across the entire backend/web/mobile stack Skills: Swift, UIKit, SwiftUI, The Composable Architecture, SPM, Combine, iPadOS, iOS on macOS, Apollo, GraphQL, Firebase, Prisma, Typescript, React, Fastlane, CircleCI, Figma

iOS Developer at PeixeUrbano (Florianópolis - Remote, 2019-2021)

Peixe Urbano (Groupon LATAM) was an e-commerce company focused on the sale of coupons and discount codes in Latin America

- Did large refactors to move the codebase out of legacy Objective-C into Swift
- Led efforts to adopt code quality standards like unit testing, snapshot testing, linting and dependency injection
- Moved the code and app architecture from a UIKit-only app to a SwiftUI+UIKit hybrid app to help the development team deliver features faster
- Helped bridging and porting Groupon's React Native apps to Peixe Urbano's native codebase Skills: iOS, MVC, MVVM, SwiftUI, UIKit, Objective-C, Carthage, CocoaPods, Fastlane, TestFlight

CocoaHeads SP / Online Chapter Leader, NSBrazil lead organizer (2018-present)

CocoaHeads is an international iOS developer community with a big presence in Brazil. NSBrazil is our nationwide Apple Platforms developer conference.

- Lead organizer and open source maintainer for NSBrazil, collaborating with other organizers and volunteers to try to make the best conference possible for the community
- Planning and executing monthly meetups in São Paulo, collaborating with companies and sourcing speakers to give talks and unite the iOS community in the largest city in South America
- Providing help for the leaders of other chapters with content production for our YouTube channel, sourcing speakers and also giving talks at their events

Skills: public speaking, web development, content production, OBS, photography, open source, iOS, iPadOS, Mac Catalyst, Jekyll, GitHub Pages, Cloudflare Functions

iOS Developer at Concrete (São Paulo, 2017-2019)

Concrete was a software consultancy firm based in São Paulo with major clients in the banking and entertainment industries. It was later bought by and integrated into Accenture.

- Led development for the iOS app for a major credit card company, moving the codebase from a monolithic project to a modularized CocoaPods approach and refactored outdated dependencies out of the codebase
- Contributed with engineers to bring features to an entertainment app with tight deadlines tied to TV shows' release schedules
- Architected server-driven UI for a shopping mall app, collaborating with backend and Android engineers to get everyone on the same page

Skils: Swift, UIKit, SnapKit, Firebase, CocoaPods, Carthage, Server-driven UI, MVC, Xcode, Scrum

Co-founder at Rowbots/Dedig (2014-2017)

Dedig was an education startup focused on creating edu games with strong analytics tools to help teachers understand their students in a more organic way

- Built the prototypes we used to pitch investors and evolved them all the way to the finished product that reached kids' hands
- Led design and development teams for Dedig and other internal projects at Rowbots
- Developed infrastructure that minimized developer downtime when working with large projects
- Implemented native iOS and Android app bridges for use within Unity3D

Skills: Unity3D, Xcode, Objective-C++, Android, Javascript, VueJS, Android Studio, Java, Game development

talks

Desenvolvendo seu primeiro jogo com SpriteKit (Developing your first game with SpriteKit) CocoaHeads Vitória - **YouTube**

education

FATEC São Caetano do Sul (2012-2016)

Tecnologia em Jogos Digitais (Game Development Technologies)